

Contact

Portfolio

https://dinbabia.pythonanywhere.com/

Phone

0956-755-9401

Email

dinbabia@gmail.com

Address

Capisnon Kauswagan, Cagayan de Oro City

Technical Skills

- Web Automation (Selenium, Playwright)
- API Testing (ReadyAPI, Python-Gauge, Insomnia, Postman)
- Writing Test Plan, Test Scenarios, and Test Cases
- Web Development (Django, Laravel)
- Python, C#, Javascript, PHP
- Load Testing (Locusts)
- MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle Database, MongoDB, Sqlite3
- Basic Penetration Testing (nmap, Burp Suite, XSS)
- Docker, GIT, CI/CD Pipeline
- Test Automation Framework (pytest, NUnit, gauge)

Soft Skills

- Teamwork, Communication and Adaptability
- Social and Emotional Intelligence
- Leadership and Goal Setter
- Growth Mindset and Work Ethic

Din Laurence C. Babia

Willing to learn and to improve in different fields of expertise; compassionate and hard-working with leadership and strong interpersonal skills for a good relation in society. The will to help others and to do more is my Atenean way.

Experience

O August 2022 - Present

Curo Teknika Inc. | Pasig, 1605 Metro Manila

Junior Software Quality Engineer (Specialist)

Duties and Responsibilities:

- Deployed to Maya Project, primarily on the Merchant Onboarding Team as Tester.
- Optimized the established automated test scripts in gauge-python; the five-day regression test was cut down to three days.
- Aligned the regression test scripts with big sweeping changes in our onboarding procedure to support old and new variations.
- Added new test scripts for every additional test cases and scenarios.
- Executed smoke tests for every new deployment
- Created test scenarios to be used for User Acceptance Testing (UAT) to the customers/users
- Verified that data are saved correctly in all databases for every transaction
- Built and created new automation scripts from scratch for 3 different services to be added to our regression tests.
- Migrated our tests from ReadyAPI (API Testing platform), which is no longer supported due to its high cost, to gauge-python.

August 2021 - August 2022

Innovuze Solutions, Inc. I Cagayan de Oro, 9000 Misamis Oriental

Software Quality Assurance Engineer

Duties and Responsibilities:

- Review and approve software or applications and ensure that they meet the quality requirements and expectations of the client and customers prior to release.
- To be able to perform both Automated and Manual "Black Box Testing"
- To develop and create Test Plans and Test Cases.
- To write, detect and document bugs before and after a code release.
- Ensure that bug fixes and features are verified before the release of the software.
- To work closely with the developers, project manager, and teammates on projects.
- To apply Agile Methodology and Principles in QA Processes

Special Tasks:

- Improved Automation Coding Standards in NUnit and Selenium C#
- Manage and train OJT-QA and Newly Hired QA Engineers

5 February 2021 - June 2021

DEPARTMENT OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY REGION X - Technical Services (Regional Standards and Testing Laboratory)

Project Assistant I (Calibration Officer)

May 2019 - August 2019
ZION DIAGNOSTICS SOLUTIONS, INC.
Service Field Engineer

EDUCATIONAL ATTAINMENT

Xavier University - Ateneo de Cagayan

Bachelor of Science in Electronics Engineering (June 2013 - March 2018)

LICENSES

Licensed Electronics Engineer (ECE) Board of October 2018

SIDE PROJECTS

O Pytest - Selenium Build

https://github.com/dinbabia/pytest_selenium_build

O Pytest - Playwright Build

https://github.com/dinbabia/pytest_playwright_build

O Automate generation of payslips to be used by a certain company.

https://github.com/dinbabia/Payroll (private)

O Generate randomly given parameters to be used for solving a circuit problem.

https://github.com/dinbabia/CircuitQuiz

O CMS Website using Laravel v.9.0

https://github.com/Team-Inun-unan/cms (private)

Training and Certificates

- O Django for Everybody Specialization via Coursera (May 2023)
- O Using JavaScript, JQuery, and JSON in Django via Coursera (May 2023)
- O Django Features and Libraries via Coursera (Apr. 2023)
- O Building Web Applications in Django via Coursera (Mar. 2023)
- O Web Application Technologies and Django via Coursera (Mar. 2023)
- O Crash Course on Python by Google via Coursera (Nov. 2022)
- O Python Advanced Certification Course by Programming Hub (June 2022)
- O Basic Linux by MNET-IT.com (November 2021)
- O Basic Python by MNET-IT.com (November 2021)
- O Master IP Addressing and Subnetting for CCNA by MNET-IT.com (November 2021)
- O "CHIP Framework: 'PROTECT' week Ensuring a Secured Digital Economy" by IECEP/DICT/Cybersecurity Bureau (June 2021)